in [7]

SERGEY ZOLOTUKHIN

(832) 380-1753 • Houston, TX • zolotukhinsereg@gmail.com



SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Full Stack Web Developer, skilled in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks. With seven years of technical experience in Drilling and Geosciences, I have learned how to analyze data and make fast, critical decisions for preventing additional expenses or eliminating chances of industrial disasters. Fluent in Russian, US citizen. Natural problem solver seeking a new path in life, not just a job.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

alcoholOK 2.0 - Github | Demo

Online collection of Cocktail recipes developed with React-Redux and Rails API.

- Developed Rails API backend with endpoints for cocktails and ingredients.
- Used Middleware, Redux-Promise in application to retrieve data from Back-End and to perform RESTFUL services.
- Maintained states in the stores and dispatched the actions using Redux.

States Map - Github | Demo

Interactive USA map for enthusiastic travelers.

- Developed Rails API backend with endpoints for users and states.
- Built dynamic and interactive frontend in Vanilla JavaScript.
- Utilized fetch, AJAX calls for implementing Client-Server Communication.

alcoholOK - Github | Demo

Online collection of Cocktail recipes fully developed in Ruby on Rails.

- Developed an application from scratch using Rails and various gems.
- Implemented many-to-many relationship, data validations, RESTful URLs.
- Integrated third party user authentication.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React.js, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, SQLite, PostgreSQL.

Currently studying: Python, Angular, Firebase.

EXPERIENCE

Scientific Drilling International, Houston TX

Technical Services Technician

(Jun 2014 – Jun 2021)

- Served 24/7 as a technical focal point for MagTraC, MWD QA/QC inquiries to prevent delays and additional drilling operations costs.
- Performed pre-drilling, real-time, and post-run checks of survey programs, appropriate corrections, magnetic model values, and other reference data critical to improving wellbore positioning and production efficiency.
- Assisted in resolving customer issues by investigating problems, preparing reports, making recommendations to management.

Testing Laboratory of Engineering at Karaganda State Technical University, Kazakhstan

Geotechnical Engineer

(Sep 2011 – Jan 2013)

- Developed algorithms for rapid X-Ray Spectrometry analysis of mineral resources for national production companies.
- Rendered methodical and consulting help for scientific research, development of engineering works, marketing research, trial tests of new product samples and materials.
- Co-author of two innovation patents: "X-Ray Fluorescence analysis of the sulfur content of coal" June 25, 2013, #27186 and "Method for the control of the effective atomic number of the substance" Aug 3, 2012, #26115 registered by Committee on Intellectual Property Rights of the Ministry of Justice of Kazakhstan.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development (Ruby on Rails, JavaScript online program)

(Mar 2020 – Jan 2021)

Karaganda State Technical University, Department of Mining, Karaganda, Kazakhstan

Master of Technics and Technology in Geology and Exploration Deposits of Minerals

(Jan 2013)

Bachelor of Geology and Prospecting of Mineral Deposits

(Jun 2011)